Mss.Rec.112 Mss.Rec.112
American Philosophical Society
Hualapai texts and sentence structure
1979
Mss.Rec.112
American Philosophical Society
4.0 Tape(s)
Linguistic recordings and instructional texts made by Akira Yamamoto in 1974 in Peach Springs, Arizona. Tapes 1-3 of this collection contain sample sentences spoken separately by Jane Honga and Maude Synilla. Tape 4 contains a reading of three texts, "Hualapai Sounds," "Let's Learn How to Write and Read in Hualapai," and "Nach Posvchyu (I am a cat)," written and read by Akira Yamamoto and Jane Honga.
4 sound cassettes (2 hr., 26 min.): analog, 1 7/8 ips, stereo.
Honga, Jane C.
Synilla, Maude
Yamamoto, Akira Y.
Related Archival Materials
A project report, articles, and the text for "Let's Learn How to Write and Read in Hualapai" and "Nach Posvchyu (I am a cat)" are available in the Phillips Fund Collection (Mss.497.3.Am4).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Akira Yamamoto in 1979 (Acc. 1979 75rec). This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Hualapai language; Hualapai language--Study and teaching; Sound recordings
- Audio recordings
  - Hualapai: Sample Sentences [1 of 2], 1974; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:35; Synilla, Maude; Yamamoto, Akira Y.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Audiocassette) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Hualapai language; Peach Springs (Ariz.)
  - Hualapai: Sample Sentences [2 of 2], 1974; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:48; Synilla, Maude; Yamamoto, Akira Y.
  - Hualapai: Sample Sentences [1 of 3], 1974; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:42; Honga, Jane C.; Yamamoto, Akira Y.
  - Hualapai: Sample Sentences [2 of 3], 1974; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:15; Honga, Jane C.; Yamamoto, Akira Y.
  - Hualapai: Sample Sentences [3 of 3], 1974; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:31; Honga, Jane C.; Yamamoto, Akira Y.
  - Let's Learn How to Write and Read in Hualapai, 1974; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:49; Yamamoto, Akira Y.
    Scope and Contents note
    A reading of a Hualapai language instructional text by Jane C. Honga and Akira Y. Yamamoto.
    Hualapai language--Glossaries, vocabularies, etc.; Hualapai language--Study and teaching; Peach Springs (Ariz.)
  - Hualapai Sounds, 1974; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:15; Yamamoto, Akira Y.
    Hualapai language; Hualapai language--Pronunciation; Hualapai language--Study and teaching; Peach Springs (Ariz.)
  - Nach Posvchyu: Book I, 1974; 04-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:39; Honga, Jane C.; Yamamoto, Akira Y.
  - Nach Posvchyu: Book II, 1974; 04-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:54; Honga, Jane C.; Yamamoto, Akira Y.